pankogut.com 2019-08-03

# Privacy Policy - PanKogut

August 3, 2017February 12, 2019

Your privacy is critically important to us. At PanKogut, we have a few fundamental principles:

  * We are thoughtful about the personal information we ask you to provide and the personal information that we collect about you through the operation of our services.
  * We store personal information for only as long as we have a reason to keep it.
  * We aim to make it as simple as possible for you to control what information on your website is shared publicly (or kept private), indexed by search engines, and permanently deleted.
  * We help protect you from overreaching government demands for your personal information.
  * We aim for full transparency on how we gather, use, and share your personal information.

Below is our Privacy Policy, which incorporates and clarifies these principles.

### Who We Are and What This Policy Covers

We are WordPress Service who helps Bloggers and Artists to get their space out there. We believe in powering the open Internet with code that is open source and are proud to say that the vast majority of our work is available under the GPL.

This Privacy Policy applies to information that we collect about you when you use:

  * Our websites (pankogut.com and pankogut.com/pro);

Throughout this Privacy Policy we’ll refer to our website and other products and services collectively as “Services.” And if you’d like to learn more about which PanKogut company is the controller of information about you, take a look at the section below on Controllers and Responsible Companies.

Below we explain how we collect, use, and share information about you, along with the choices that you have with respect to that information.

### Creative Commons Sharealike License

This Privacy Policy is available under a [Creative Commons Sharealike](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/) license. The licence was made by [Automattic](https://automattic.com/privacy/). You’re more than welcome to copy it, adapt it, and repurpose it for your own use. Just make sure to revise the language so that your policy reflects your actual practices.

### Information We Collect

We only collect information about you if we have a reason to do so–for example, to provide our Services, to communicate with you, or to make our Services better.

We collect information in three ways: if and when you provide information to us, automatically through operating our Services, and from outside sources. Let’s go over the information that we collect.

#### _Information You Provide to Us_

It’s probably no surprise that we collect information that you provide to us. The amount and type of information depends on the context and how we use the information. Here are some examples:

  * **Newsletter:** We ask for your email for our weekly newsletter only to send you an email every week with deals and update about our Service.
  * **Communications With Us (Hi There!):** You may also provide us information when you respond to surveys, communicate with our support team and when you send to us general comunications via our contact form.

#### _Information We Collect Automatically_

We also collect some information automatically:

  * **Information from Cookies & Other Technologies:** A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. Pixel tags (also called web beacons) are small blocks of code placed on websites and emails. PanKogut uses cookies and other technologies like pixel tags to help us identify and track visitors, usage, and access preferences for our Services, as well as track and understand email campaign effectiveness and to deliver targeted ads.

#### _Information We Collect from Other Sources_

  * **Basic Account Information:** If you want to get one of our Service we may collect basic information via the third service Gumroad where you can read their [Privacy Policy](https://gumroad.com/privacy).

### How And Why We Use Information

#### _Purposes for Using Information_

We use information about you as mentioned above and for the purposes listed below:

  * To provide our Services–for example our plans via Gumroad;
  * To monitor and analyze trends and better understand how users interact with our Services, which helps us improve our Services and make them easier to use;
  * To measure, gauge, and improve the effectiveness of our advertising, and better understand user retention and attrition–for example, we may analyze how many individuals purchased a plan after receiving a marketing message or the features used by those who continue to use our Services after a certain length of time;
  * To communicate with you, for example through an email, about offers and promotions offered by PanKogut and others we think will be of interest to you, solicit your feedback, or keep you up to date on PanKogut and our products;

#### _Legal Bases for Collecting and Using Information_

A note here for those in the European Union about our legal grounds for processing information about you under EU data protection laws, which is that our use of your information is based on the grounds that:

(1) The use is necessary in order to fulfill our commitments to you under our Terms of Service or other agreements with you or is necessary to administer your account on Gumroad–for example, in order to charge you for a paid plan; or

(2) The use is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation; or

(3) The use is necessary in order to protect your vital interests or those of another person; or

(4) We have a legitimate interest in using your information–for example, to provide and update our Services, to improve our Services so that we can offer you an even better user experience, to safeguard our Services, to communicate with you, to measure, gauge, and improve the effectiveness of our advertising, and better understand user retention and attrition, to monitor and prevent any problems with our Services, and to personalize your experience; or

(5) You have given us your consent–for example before we place certain cookies on your device and access and analyze them later on.

### Sharing Information

#### _How We Share Information_

We do not sell our users’ private personal information.

We share information about you in the limited circumstances spelled out below and with appropriate safeguards on your privacy:

  * **Subsidiaries, Employees, and Independent Contractors:** We may disclose information about you to our subsidiaries, our employees, and individuals who are our independent contractors that need to know the information in order to help us provide our Services or to process the information on our behalf. We require our subsidiaries, employees, and independent contractors to follow this Privacy Policy for personal information that we share with them.
  * **Third Party Vendors:** We may share information about you with third party vendors who need to know information about you in order to provide their services to us, or to provide their services to you or your site. This group includes vendors that help us provide our Services to you (like payment providers that process your credit and debit card information, fraud prevention services that allow us to analyze fraudulent payment transactions, postal and email delivery services that help us stay in touch with you, customer chat and email support services that help us communicate with you), those that assist us with our marketing efforts (e.g. by providing tools for identifying a specific marketing target group or improving our marketing campaigns), those that help us understand and enhance our Services (like analytics providers), and companies that make products available on our websites (such as Gumroad), who may need information about you in order to, for example, provide technical or other support services to you. We require vendors to agree to privacy commitments in order to share information with them.
  * **To Protect Rights, Property, and Others:** We may disclose information about you when we believe in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of **PanKogut** , third parties, or the public at large.
  * **Business Transfers:** In connection with any merger, sale of company assets, or acquisition of all or a portion of our business by another company, or in the unlikely event that PanKogut goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, user information would likely be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. If any of these events were to happen, this Privacy Policy would continue to apply to your information and the party receiving your information may continue to use your information, but only consistent with this Privacy Policy.
  * **With Your Consent:** We may share and disclose information with your consent or at your direction.

#### _Information Shared Publicly_

Information that you choose to make public is–you guessed it–disclosed publicly.

We use Disqus for comments on our blog section.

Public information may also be indexed by search engines or used by third parties.

Please keep all of this in mind when deciding what you would like to share.

### How Long We Keep Information

We generally discard information about you when we no longer need the information for the purposes for which we collect and use it–which are described in the section above on How and Why We Use Information–and we are not legally required to continue to keep it.

As another example, when you delete a comment from our website, it will be delete immediatly.

### Security

While no online service is 100% secure, we work very hard to protect information about you against unauthorized access, use, alteration, or destruction, and take reasonable measures to do so, such as monitoring our Services for potential vulnerabilities and attacks.

### Choices

You have several choices available when it comes to information about you:

  * **Limit the Information that You Provide:** If you have an account with Gumroad, you can choose not to provide the optional account information, profile information, and transaction and billing information. Please keep in mind that if you do not provide this information, certain features of our Services–for example, paid, premium themes–may not be accessible.
  * **Opt-Out of Electronic Communications:** You may opt out of receiving promotional messages from us. Just follow the instructions in those messages. If you opt out of promotional messages, we may still send you other messages, like those about your account and legal notices.
  * **Set Your Browser to Reject Cookies:** At this time, PanKogut does not respond to “do not track” signals across all of our Services. However, you can usually choose to set your browser to remove or reject browser cookies before using PanKogut’s websites, with the drawback that certain features of PanKogut’s websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.
  * **Close Your Account:** While we’d be very sad to see you go, if you no longer want to use our Services 🙁 🙁 🙁 :(, you can easily close your Gumroad account. Please keep in mind that we may continue to retain your information after closing your account, as described in How Long We Keep Information above–for example, when that information is reasonably needed to comply with (or demonstrate our compliance with) legal obligations such as law enforcement requests, or reasonably needed for our legitimate business interests.

### Your Rights

If you are located in certain countries, including those that fall under the scope of the European General Data Protection Regulation (AKA the “GDPR”), data protection laws give you rights with respect to your personal data, subject to any exemptions provided by the law, including the rights to:

  * Request access to your personal data;
  * Request correction or deletion of your personal data;
  * Object to our use and processing of your personal data;
  * Request that we limit our use and processing of your personal data; and
  * Request portability of your personal data.

You can usually access, correct, or delete your personal data using your account settings and tools that Gumroad offer, but if you aren’t able to do that, or you would like to contact us about one of the other rights, scroll down to How to Reach Us to, well, find out how to reach us.

EU individuals also have the right to make a complaint to a government supervisory authority.

### Controllers and Responsible Companies

Depending on the Services you use, more than one company may be the controller of your personal data. Generally, the “controller” is the italian company PanKogut that entered into the contract with you under the Terms of Service for the the product or service you use.

### How to Reach Us

If you have a question about this Privacy Policy, or you would like to contact us about any of the rights mentioned in the Your Rights section above, please [contact us](mailto:privacy@pankogut.com).

### Other Things You Should Know (Keep Reading!)

#### _Transferring Information_

Because PanKogut’s Services are offered worldwide, the information about you that we process when you use the Services in the EU may be used, stored, and/or accessed by individuals operating outside the European Economic Area (EEA) who work for us, other members of our group of companies, or third party data processors. This is required for the purposes listed in the How and Why We Use Information section above. When providing information about you to entities outside the EEA, we will take appropriate measures to ensure that the recipient protects your personal information adequately in accordance with this Privacy Policy as required by applicable law. These measures include:

  * In the case of US based entities, entering into European Commission approved standard contractual arrangements with them, or ensuring they have signed up to the [EU-US Privacy Shield](https://www.privacyshield.gov/welcome); or
  * In the case of entities based in other countries outside the EEA, entering into European Commission approved standard contractual arrangements with them.

You can ask us for more information about the steps we take to protect your personal information when transferring it from the EU.

#### _Ads and Analytics Services Provided by Others_

Ads appearing on any of our Services may be delivered by advertising networks. Other parties may also provide analytics services via our Services. These ad networks and analytics providers may set tracking technologies (like cookies) to collect information about your use of our Services and across other websites and online services. These technologies allow these third parties to recognize your device to compile information about you or others who use your device. This information allows us and other companies to, among other things, analyze and track usage, determine the popularity of certain content, and deliver advertisements that may be more targeted to your interests. Please note this Privacy Policy only covers the collection of information by PanKogut and does not cover the collection of information by any third party advertisers or analytics providers.

### Privacy Policy Changes

Although most changes are likely to be minor, PanKogut may change its Privacy Policy from time to time. PanKogut encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. If we make changes, we will notify you by revising the change log below, and, in some cases, we may provide additional notice. Your further use of the Services after a change to our Privacy Policy will be subject to the updated policy.

That’s it! Thanks for reading.

### Change log

  * _May 25, 2018:_ added information to reflect the requirements of the EU’s General Data Protection Regulation.
